<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>Train of Thoughts to Tuscany</title>
 <link href="http://www.rue-tuscany.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://www.rue-tuscany.com"/>
 <updated>2011-05-20T20:55:10-04:00</updated>
 <id>http://www.rue-tuscany.com/</id>
 <author>
   <name>Jennifer Lee</name>
   <email>leecarrot@gmail.com</email>
 </author>
 
 
 <entry>
   <title>Niece and Grandmother</title>
   <link href="http://www.rue-tuscany.com/random/thesis/niece-grandma.html"/>
   <updated>2011-05-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>id:/random/thesis/niece-grandma</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was overjoyed when my niece was born last year. We had been waiting for months, and our wish was fulfilled exactly on Sunday, October 10, 2010. She is a 7 month old baby now, and she looks healthy and active. I let my mother and grandmother know about my intention of becoming a godmother for my niece. They quickly laughed it off, explaining the responsibilities I had to bear in that case. Actually, I don&amp;#8217;t think it is such a bad idea, because I am not sure if I will be able to have a family of my own one day. Considering my status of being a student, I am obviously not ready to be a godmother &amp;#8211; not when I&amp;#8217;m economically incapable. Regardless, I will revisit this idea again in the near future :-). She is just so adorable ^_^. Prior to this, I even considered sponsoring a child!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src='/images/grandmother-niece.jpg' alt='alt niece&amp;amp;grandma' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a related note, I just found out that my grandmother was admitted to hospital, and it is still unclear to me when that happened. She was still home when I talked to her four days ago. She did tell me about the partial numbness felt in her right palm and the sole of her feet for the first time last Saturday. I managed to get hold of my sister online yesterday. We were too excited about her baby on the webcam that I forgot to inquiry more details of my grandmother. I was looking forward to talk to my grandmother later in the evening, however, she was not available. So I called home and found out that she was still in the hospital. Based on the brief description from my sister, the doctor was uncertain of the right treatment as her blood pressure changed rapidly. They had to observe her condition every two hours to find out whether a given treatment was effective. I will suggest my sister to get a second opinion whenever possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This incident serves to remind me that I really don&amp;#8217;t have much time left. I would like to go back to Jakarta after defending my thesis. By next week, I hope I can have everything planned out for my thesis and write a report to my advisor who&amp;#8217;s going to be away for that week. And by the end of May, preferably, I need to have some results that can be analyzed, so that when my advisor is gone for the whole June, I can spend time to write and wrap up my thesis. I may not be able to submit my thesis by the end of June, but at least I have something working and part of the writing that I can slowly build up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has been a little more than 3 months since I arrived back in Canada. I had to return to Jakarta in mid August last year when my grandfather passed away. It had never come across my mind to come home in such manner. It was a very sudden event which none of us could foresee. Just a week before, he came back from a family reunion (from Taiwan and Bali) for which I was unable to join. He must have been exhausted and deprieved of good rest. I stayed with my grandmother for almost six months from that moment on. I have been so paralyzed with regards to my thesis. Perhaps I should have given it up a long time ago had I known that it doesn&amp;#8217;t matter how much time I have, I still find enormous amount of internal barrier to get it done&amp;#8230; On the other hand, my grandfather would have loved to see me finishing my thesis. I think I shall finish it for him, my family who has been supporting me all these time, and also for advisor and myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class='image_and_caption'&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img title='Teddy Bear Companion' src='/images/richie.png' alt='teddy' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;b&gt;This teddy is a gift from my grandparents when I was 8 years old in the 1990. She has been my loyal companion. It's funny how my grandfather supported me to bring the teddy -- twice during my move to live with my parents and to Canada -- even though grandma didn't think it was a good idea :-).&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought a whole lot of what could have been last week &amp;#8211; like how I should have tried to earn sufficient work experience in Canada before going home for good. I wasted so many years in school which could have been spent working and gathering points to apply for permanent residency. Had I not been always undecided, a citizenship might have been a reality right now. That has never been my main priority, but it would have made it so much easier to visit other countries and be respected a little more when you enter another country (at least they won&amp;#8217;t have to stop you for the luggage). This sounds like the Law of Sunk Cost&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no way back and I am not getting younger to fix things. People say it is always difficult to start over. I find it so true. Reiterating my focus again, they should be: 1) To go home to accompany grandmother once I&amp;#8217;m done here. 2) Regardless of whether I can find a related job to my field, there&amp;#8217;s always a way out. I can help my brother on the software side to run my mother&amp;#8217;s restaurant (he may not need to pay someone else to do that anymore). At the same time, I can keep learning on my own, enter some challenge, contribute to Open Source Project, and hopefully be eligible to participate in Google Summer of Code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The near future is hard to tell, and there will be many variables that come into the picture. Hence, while trying to prioritize the above things, it&amp;#8217;s better to aim for small things at once and see where they lead to. I have been constantly worried of my grandmother since I left home, and I often feel so running out of time. Let&amp;#8217;s hope for the best&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;object height='40' width='300'&gt;&lt;param name='movie' value='http://grooveshark.com/songWidget.swf' /&gt;&lt;param name='wmode' value='window' /&gt;&lt;param name='allowScriptAccess' value='always' /&gt;
&lt;param name='flashvars' value='hostname=cowbell.grooveshark.com&amp;songIDs=30509069&amp;style=grass&amp;p=0' /&gt;
&lt;embed src='http://grooveshark.com/songWidget.swf' allowScriptAccess='always' type='application/x-shockwave-flash' wmode='window' height='40' flashvars='hostname=cowbell.grooveshark.com&amp;songIDs=30509069&amp;style=grass&amp;p=0' width='300' /&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wrapping up, I am going to briefly touch on the food of the week. I have found that avocados, strawberries, 12 Grain or Ancient Grain Wheat Bread, with or without microwaved egg and any cheese are perfect choice for easy breakfast/brunch, or snack. In fact, they are healthy combination and good for anytime. Avocados and strawberries are generally expensive here. Nonetheless, since crackers, chips/tortillas and instant soup are not well suited for my needs and health (due to the amount of sodium and dryness, and even though they claim to contain Omega 3 and fibers), it is alright to spend more on the fruits and wheat bread instead. Below are snapshots of what I had this afternoon with Ceylon Jasmine Green Tea. The cheese is Jarlsberg imported from Norway, which is quite similar to Swiss cheese. The unpeeled avocado and strawberries inside the container are left overs I saved for another day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src='/images/comfort-food.jpg' alt='alt food of the week' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Tapping into the Spring</title>
   <link href="http://www.rue-tuscany.com/inspiration/into-spring.html"/>
   <updated>2011-05-07T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>id:/inspiration/into-spring</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;code&gt;Two activities: one at the beginning, one at the end.&lt;/code&gt; &amp;#8211; Pema Chodron &amp;#8211;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the morning when you wake up, you reflect on the day ahead and aspire to use it to keep a wide-open heart and mind. At the end of the day, before going to sleep, you think over what you have done. If you fulfilled your aspiration, even once, rejoice in that. If you went against your aspiration, rejoice that you are able to see what you did and are no longer living in ignorance. This way you will be inspired to go forward with increasing clarity, confidence, and compassion in the days that follow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class='image_and_caption'&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img title='Lavender Wax Bear' src='/images/lavender-bear.jpg' alt='mother&amp;apos;s day' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spring is too short to miss out. We experience a slightly late and cold Spring this year with a lot of precipitation. Today and last Thursday, I managed to pick up my camera again. I am very happy to have captured those little things in our backyard. The annual Tulip Festival has started. I&amp;#8217;m not sure if I will be able to go and see the flowers this year. I have been trying to set a deadline as late as the end of June to submit my thesis. At the same time, I need to ask myself how realistic this goal is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class='image_and_caption'&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img title='Happy Mother&amp;apos;s Day' src='/images/mothers-day.jpg' alt='mother&amp;apos;s day' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>How To Let Them Be Weight Off Your Shoulders?</title>
   <link href="http://www.rue-tuscany.com/well-being/letting-go.html"/>
   <updated>2011-04-30T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>id:/well-being/letting-go</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The passing week has been intense to me. I was too fixated on certain things and didn&amp;#8217;t anticipate any disruptions to my plan. The result has been a rather chaotic week all the way down. I developed tiredness, and my sleep schedule was wreaked havoc given that I went to bed almost at dawn. In one occasion, some unknown guy was being very rude to me. I was looking for a way to get back to highway after dropping off my uncle to pick up his new car. As the street was crowded at that moment, I was unable to make a direct left turn to the route that usually brings me home. I went a bit further &amp;#8211; one traffic light ahead &amp;#8211; and I was able to make a left turn to a small street. I soon realized that I could make a U turn, before eventually turning right to the main street, which would bring me back to the highway. So I did that almost instantly as the opposite road was clear. But I forgot to make a left signal in doing so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What happened next was a little bizzare and disheartening. I was definitely at fault for forgetting to turn on the signal, and I have to keep this in mind to be more careful next time. The reaction I got stayed in my head for a bit that evening&amp;#8230; It was not just the loud horning coming from the car behind me, but the words uttered from the stranger behind the wheel. For a long time, even my own family members and friends have never treated me that way. On the other hand, I have encountered many good samaritans. I need to be prepared to face similar things in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I talked about what happened to my aunt, and she&amp;#8217;s very understanding. Then I discussed it with his husband (my uncle) as it had always been the case for the past years. His feedback was not very positive, but I agreed with him regarding my carelessness. He also pointed out other things that I&amp;#8217;m not doing well. For example, how close I position myself to the driving wheel. He always tells me that I&amp;#8217;m not relaxed enough. I wouldn&amp;#8217;t think so at first, because my legs are not long enough. I also don&amp;#8217;t think I sit extremely close to the wheel as he demonstrated. I took his words before, and have adjusted the distance over the course of several years, each time a little farther back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was indeed nervous five years ago when I started. Ever since, I have always driven the way I thought was comfortable that allowed me to have more control of the car without any problems. Is it a matter of preferences? I started to think about it, but I&amp;#8217;m not sure if it will in fact be more effective if I adjust the position farther than it is now . Perhaps I need to drive that way long enough in order to see if they work for me. I tried his suggestion in the past, but found it harder to control the car. Moreover, everytime he sat next to me when I drove, I became nervous although I really appreciated that he cautioned myself to any dangerous situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edited&lt;/strong&gt;: OK, I was in a miserable mood while writing this post (accumulation of the same issues for several years), and I&amp;#8217;m really not good at handling criticism. I should really let it go despite how he decided to portrait me negatively to my family. I need to think about my aunt who has been giving me a home to stay and grow in Canada all these years. The little things should be negligable, and I always have a choice not to let them affect me. Only when I&amp;#8217;m truly done with my study, my happiness and freedom will no longer be tied to compromise and pretense. Never take it for granted when we can still live together with our parents, brothers/sisters, and grandparents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#8217;s a tremendous difficulty in differentiating between genuine, objective criticism from the ones that are not. I lost a good friend because I couldn&amp;#8217;t stand her constant dissatisfaction. I simply disappeared. Looking back, things didn&amp;#8217;t have to unfold that way. There are times in our life that we need someone who cares enough to criticize. Perhaps we would still be hanging out together if I had asked her for suggestions on the things I could improve. The criticism were perceived as hard, because I didn&amp;#8217;t know how to react to them. I felt I had no other choice other than losing my true self. What else I could have done when she told me she&amp;#8217;s tired to hear my story. It was hard to pretend that things were good while they were not as a matter of fact. I miss the time when we spent the weekends studying together at the library until late at night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wish someone would tell me if I was simply delusional and too sensitive. Is there a way to tell whether a criticism is indeed an objective and constructive one, or it simply comes from the person who dislikes you, the one who has grown tired of you? How to go to the bed at night without carrying all these thoughts with you? I just feel the need to address this root of sadness. I am afraid that I still do not know how to deal with it if the very same issue presents itself in my future relationships. Life does not feel like life if I always feel like a coward, running away from potential friends. I have thought of meditation as one way to improve my situation, but it is not easy to practice mindful meditation.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Week 3 Roundup, April</title>
   <link href="http://www.rue-tuscany.com/well-being/productivity/weekend-roundup.html"/>
   <updated>2011-04-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>id:/well-being/productivity/weekend-roundup</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;While I&amp;#8217;m starting to see more ways to save money and eat healthy at the same time, that&amp;#8217;s pretty much the only improvement I made this month. It occurs to me that there are many things I can&amp;#8217;t do right. Things like procrastination is obvious. As soon as I regret it, the endless vicious cycle starts all over again. There are great insights from various sources into why one procrastinates. In my case, I notice the lack of self control, gravitation towards immediate rewards, and I grow tired of solving problems that usually take days. Hence, I&amp;#8217;ve developed a strong aversion to doing things. Not doing is also not the solution, because it will come back to haunt you and you can&amp;#8217;t move on. The worst case that can happen if I keep doing&amp;#8230; is actually not bad at all, or nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here goes a short note to self and a reminder to keep working on the weak points:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Minimize excessive worries. I have to acknowledge that there&amp;#8217;s no way to please everyone with regards to what I write, tweet, or how I view things. The online world has been nice to me. But I still think too much. I&amp;#8217;m struggling to adjust my expectation, and to focus more doing things for myself and for the people who are willing to accept them.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;In light of point 1, it is important to be the original me. This implies creativity in every situation. I haven&amp;#8217;t done that enough with my Tumblr blog, and I&amp;#8217;m slowly changing it.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Things do not have to be big, as long as they are original. The difficulty is that many things build on others, and cultivating the complete understanding without diluting the basic principles is a challenge. For example, a thesis always builds on the previous work. Sometimes you no longer know what you are doing, and you lost the confidence half way.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Write three A4 pages everyday. They can be anything that comes to mind. Think of this routine as a training to think less and do more without reservation, without expectation of being perfect.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Completion is a step closer when the ideas are no longer abstract.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;When I was little, my granduncle suggested to dedicate more time to practice specific parts of a piano piece that I was not good at. Until now, there&amp;#8217;s this inherent tendency to avoid the unknowns.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class='image_and_caption'&gt;
  &lt;b&gt;Image credit © &lt;a href='http://blinksoflife.tumblr.com' target='_blank'&gt;blinks.of.life&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img title='Freedom from Life Choices' src='/images/life-choices.jpg' alt='blinks.of.life' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technology, Privacy and Analytics:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I find it rather absurd that Apple is suing Samsung for copying their technology. While I love my iPad and I consider it more robust than my Nexus on Android, I can&amp;#8217;t justify their action. Samsung is the supplier of chips Apple has been using on their products. Without Samsung, there would have been no iPhones and iPads that gain so much popularity today. In response to the lawsuit, Samsung is suing Apple on 10 counts for stealing their design. It was argued that &lt;a href='http://www.phandroid.com/2011/04/20/did-apple-really-steal-their-iphone-design-from-samsung-pot-meet-kettle/'&gt;in 2007, both Samsung and Apple released their phones at about the same time&lt;/a&gt;. The fact is probably nobody is copying anybody. Apple might have tried to obtain discount from Samsung. I see patents as barrier to new innovations. When a company is getting very succesful in amassing uncritical fans, it&amp;#8217;s easy to feel threatened by competitions. We have a long way to a selfless corporate culture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the controversy surrounding Apple, new research found that 3G iPhones and iPad devices store users&amp;#8217; locations in an unencrypted hidden file. Using &lt;a href='http://www.bytemining.com/2011/04/location-tracking-on-android-too/'&gt;different approaches&lt;/a&gt;, Google has been doing the same with their Android devices. Both companies are said to be building their location database. This has some privacy implication, however, no harm has been done so far. It is a non-issue if the location data do not fall into the hands of irresponsible parties or anyone with certain motives. &lt;a href='http://petewarden.github.com/iPhoneTracker/'&gt;iPhone Tracker&lt;/a&gt; was created to easily map the locations, and &lt;a href='http://blog.revolutionanalytics.com/2011/04/how-to-load-your-iphone-location-data-into-r.html'&gt;location data can be loaded to R&lt;/a&gt; for those who would like to do more with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On &lt;a href='http://petzoldt.tumblr.com/post/3236488086/statistical-flaws-in-twitter-mood-predicts-the-stock'&gt;Statistical Flaws: &amp;#8216;Twitter Mood Predicts the Stock Market&amp;#8217; paper&lt;/a&gt; - the lesson is that we need an objective way to measure the performance of data mining algorithms. When tested on a single data set without validating the model using separate data sets, the prediction ability will be largely exaggerated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, there is now an &lt;a href='http://www.geek.com/articles/geek-cetera/augmented-reality-app-helps-librarians-keep-the-stacks-sorted-20110421/'&gt;Android application utilizing augmented reality to help locate misplaced library books&lt;/a&gt;. An iPhone version is being developed. I&amp;#8217;m fascinated by how similar technology used in Google Goggles can do so much wonder that would be impossible prior to the iPhone era.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Image credit © &lt;a href='http://deanminifie.tumblr.com/post/4810261813/emotional-trip' target='_blank'&gt;deanminifie&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src='/images/emotional-trip.jpg' alt='alt deanminifie' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quotes of the week, courtesy of &lt;a href='http://amiquote.tumblr.com/'&gt;Lapidarium&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You’ll find out it’s little savors and little things that count more than big ones. A walk on a spring morning is better than an eighty-mile ride in a hopped-up car, you know why? Because it’s full of flavors, full of a lot of things growing. You’ve time to seek and find. I know, you’re after the broad effect now, I suppose that’s fit and proper. But you got to look at grapes as well as watermelons. You greatly admire skeletons and I like fingerprints; well, and good. Right now such things are bothersome to you, and I wonder if it isn’t because you never learned to use them. If you had your way you’d pass a law to abolish all the little jobs, the little things. But then you’d leave yourselves nothing to do between the big jobs and you’d have a devil of a time thinking up things? Cutting grass and pulling weeds can be a way of life.” — &lt;a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ray_Bradbury'&gt;Ray Bradbury&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dandelion_Wine'&gt;Dandelion Wine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You never change things by fighting the existing reality. To change something, build a new model that makes the existing model obsolete” — &lt;a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Buckminster_Fuller'&gt;Buckminster Fuller&lt;/a&gt;, American engineer, author, designer, inventor, and futurist (1895-1983)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Who knows what I want to do? Who knows what anyone wants to do? How can you be sure about something like that? Isn’t it all a question of brain chemistry, signals going back and forth, electrical energy in the cortex? How do you know whether something is really what you want to do or just some kind of nerve impulse in the brain? Some minor little activity takes place somewhere in this unimportant place in one of the brain hemispheres and suddenly I want to go to Montana or I don’t want to go to Montana.” — &lt;a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Don_DeLillo'&gt;Don DeLillo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/White_Noise_%28novel%29'&gt;White Noise&lt;/a&gt;, cited in &lt;a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jonah_Lehrer'&gt;Jonah Lehrer&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/How_We_Decide'&gt;How We Decide&lt;/a&gt;, Houghton Mifflin Harcourt, Boston, NY, 2009, p.9.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;♫ ♩ ♪ ♫ ♬ ♫ ♩ ♪ ♫ ♬ … &lt;br /&gt; My rusty rendition of &lt;a href='http://dl.dropbox.com/u/4187310/20110423_194718.wav'&gt;&amp;#8216;Horizon - from Road to Oasis, by artist Missa Johnouchi&amp;#8217;&lt;/a&gt;. It had been a long time the piano stayed covered, so it was a pretty rough recording on a late Saturday afternoon ^_^.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Nexus S</title>
   <link href="http://www.rue-tuscany.com/random/nexus-s.html"/>
   <updated>2011-04-09T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>id:/random/nexus-s</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;For a long time, I was pretty convinced that I wouldn&amp;#8217;t need a smartphone. I got my iPad 1 in June 2010, and I&amp;#8217;ve been enjoying it ever since. It&amp;#8217;s particularly useful for all my readings. I have been able to gradually reduce paper and ink usage from the use of my laser printer. My 2005 Nokia mobile phone will do the job during emergencies. It was only recently that the mobile plan is starting to get the most out of me. &lt;p&gt;Even though I went with the $10 prepaid plan, I had received telemarketing calls whenever the phone was on. Moreover, they ate up my minutes simply from the incoming calls, resulting in the $10 refill amount became insufficient to make calls sometimes. When I forgot to refill on the expiry date -- which is usually a month later -- I lost my existing balance. This has happened too often, but I was too lazy to look for a better solution. Not to mention the accumulated Fido dollars/rewards are unusable. Perhaps there is a way to block these telemarketing numbers, or there aren't any. Another way out is to get a new activation with Fido again. But I have an option not to stick with Fido, equivalent to not spending my money on a carrier that usually goes together with the Big 3 when there is now an emerging no contract, no hidden fees carriers in Canada. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So for more than two weeks now, my old cell phone has 5 cents remaining even though I haven&amp;#8217;t made any outgoing calls since the refill a month ago. I have no one to call, and I haven&amp;#8217;t encountered any difficulty on the road while driving. Although I had been able to live without a mobile phone, things can go unpredictable anytime and I definitely need to bring one with me just in case. I&amp;#8217;ve been considering to use my iPad with the &lt;a href='http://shop.windmobile.ca/ProductCatalog/Handsets/DatastickDetails.aspx?id=Huawei+E583%28WINDCA%29&amp;amp;color=blue'&gt;Windspeed Pocket Hotspot&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;#8217;s a Mifi that can serve as wireless hotspot for up to five other devices including laptop and the iPad. This way, I would then only need to sign up for a (possibly unlimited) data plan without the default talk and text plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plan was to use Skype for taking and receiving calls. It&amp;#8217;s not such an ideal solution, because Canada does not have online Skype number yet, which means that whenever people call me in Ottawa, they will actually call the US number in Ogdensburg, New York, instead of the local number. That will certainly cost more for them, but it may work if it&amp;#8217;s a short phone call and I call them back later. If not for the Android 2.3 Gingerbread platform (means one of the first to get update from Google), cleanliness and the ease of customization in Nexus S, instant camera (to take with me when going for a walk and driving) &amp;#8211; and the size of a smart/mobile phone &amp;#8211; using the combination of Skype, Mifi and iPad is much less expensive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the same time, Nexus S was only two weeks away from its official release in Canada. Two weeks later, I&amp;#8217;m really succumbing to temptation. I spent a lot of time debating with myself whether to get one or not. I decided in order to get back to work, I should just get one so I won&amp;#8217;t spend too much time mulling over it. Next time faced with similar dilemma, I have to remind myself to read Psyblog: &lt;a href='http://www.spring.org.uk/2011/04/top-10-self-control-strategies.php'&gt;Top Ten Self-Control Strategies&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Nexus One was released, I already fell in love with Google phone featuring Android OS, but I managed to resist getting one for myself last year, nor did I rush to get an iPhone 3GS or 4. With the exeception for iPad as an eReader, I was not sold at all with iPhone or iPod touch. But this year is quite different. For some reason, our wireless provider &amp;#8211; Primus Telecommunication &amp;#8211; has been blocking some websites, possibly of UK origin for almost a half year. From experience, it&amp;#8217;s hard to get them fixed it right away because they would waste your time troubleshooting unrelated things. This is unbeliavable. Since I work from home mostly, I need to test out whether the website is really down, or it actually works with other providers. I figured I could do it if I had an alternative internet connection, such as 3G.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src='/images/nexus_s-side.jpg' alt='alt nexus' /&gt; &lt;p&gt; I went to get my Nexus S yesterday afternoon. It is $25 more expensive at WindMobile, but it is still a decent price. Videotron in Quebec was the first to sell Nexus S in Canada globally. But some people had been getting the phone from Wind the day before. The news was reliable and I took the chance to visit the retailer. They have actually begun selling it even though it was listed as coming soon on their website. I will see if I can have a price adjustment if they reduce the price within the next 14 days to keep up with the competition. I was advised to go with the $45 unstoppable plan, but I didn't. It was a difficult decision. I need to test out if the $10 Social Mobile data add-on works for me. I wish there was an option to eliminate the default voice plan. I currently go with the $15, but I'm sure I'll have a lot of unused minutes :). I was told that if we go with the $20 data add-on, the total cost including voice plan and after taxes will be very close to $45. But I'm still not convinced. $45 after taxes will be more than $50. I just have to see for myself. Within a limited time, I will be able to upgrade if I need to. The total monthly payment is $25 for now. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Google Phone is supposed to be unlocked, but I don't know why they told me I can only unlock it after three months with Wind. I really need someone to confirm this. Koodo Mobile has really an attractive price at $425, $75 less expensive than others. If you go on tab, you only need to pay $275 and put the remaining amount on tab. Simply settle the outstanding balance when leaving and you can keep the phone. The tab plan may be just slightly better than a contract. They may have other ways to make profit. Besides, is the phone going to work with foreign SIM cards if I leave Canada? They had one at Best Buy yesterday, but I couldn't buy the phone outright. Instead, I would need to sign a 3 year contract for new activation with Fido. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src='/images/nexus_s-back.jpg' alt='alt nexus' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class='section'&gt;
&lt;h1 id='update_april_15_2011'&gt;Update: April 15, 2011&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After owning Nexus S for a week, I must say I&amp;#8217;m very happy with it. The Google phone turns out to be unlocked since I was able to get it to work with my old SIM card from FIDO on a 2G/EDGE network (Wind uses the AWS network). The GPS picks up my exact location. It came to my rescue when I drove pass the insurance office. In a few months time, faster processors and 3D phones will become a hype and many probably won&amp;#8217;t talk about Nexus S anymore. Regardless, the features offered by Nexus S are sufficient for my needs. Technology evolves and I have to come to terms with that. Otherwise, I&amp;#8217;ll always be waiting for that perfect phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have installed a bunch of applications including Google Goggles, Nole for light notification, and the Swype keyboard. The default keyboard is very good, but I made a lot of typing mistakes as I haven&amp;#8217;t got used to the touchscreen keyboard. Therefore, the Swype keyboard really helps. It&amp;#8217;s incrediblly responsive and I love the crisp sound it produces as we type. I don&amp;#8217;t mind the plastic feel of Nexus S. It may be less elegant than its predecessor, the Nexus One &amp;#8211; also compared to iPhone, LG, and other HTC phones &amp;#8211; but I can look at it as a benefit that contributes to the light weight and how it fits nicely in my hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Skype from the Android market didn&amp;#8217;t work as expected on the newer Gingerbread 2.3.3 OS. It didn&amp;#8217;t let me sign in. I was fortunate to have come across the hacked version of Skype that works over 3G. It would be perfect if only we could have Amazon Appstore available in Canada. Everyday, there is a different free app we can download for that particular day. I&amp;#8217;m still exploring ways to delegate tasks from my iPad and computer to the smartphone. It is like working with three monitors :-). Kindle for Android works great. I also have Dropbox and Evernote installed. How convenient to have any types of data synced across computers and mobile devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Gedit as All Purpose Text Editor and IDE</title>
   <link href="http://www.rue-tuscany.com/productivity/gedit.html"/>
   <updated>2011-04-07T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>id:/productivity/gedit</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I had been checking out Emacs. I heard a lot of good things about both Emacs and Vim. I wish I was a quick learner. Due to the time constrain and learning curve, I decided to continue using Gedit for the time being. It doesn&amp;#8217;t make a tremendeous difference whether I use Gedit or other editors, as long as I get things done. I will definitely try to pick up Emacs again in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gedit is quite a decent text editor and IDE in my opinion. The main thing that I really like about gedit is its simplicity and ease of use. It is a default editor that comes with Gnome. I recently reinstalled Latex plugin after upgrading to Ubuntu 10.10. I have also activated a number of plugins such as the Word Completion, Align for columns. I am also using it as a Python IDE. &lt;em&gt;Code Highlighting, Bracket completion, Class Browser, Embedded Terminal, Python Code Completion, Python Indentation and Better Python Console&lt;/em&gt; are among plugins that may help obtain as much seamless coding experience as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src='/images/gedit.png' alt='alt gedit' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wrote a simple Python script to make sure plugins were working properly for the first time. At a later time, who knows I needed a random number generator to decide on the mobile carrier since I don&amp;#8217;t know which plans are suitable for the Nexus S I&amp;#8217;m getting next week :-).&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Tsunami and Earthquake</title>
   <link href="http://www.rue-tuscany.com/random/astrology/japan-earthquake.html"/>
   <updated>2011-03-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>id:/random/astrology/japan-earthquake</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My heart goes out to the people of Japan dealing with the aftermath of earthquake and tsunami. May all the life lost can peacefully continue their journey to the next stage. I admire those working at the nuclear plants, and I wish them well. I believe the people of Japan will come out of this with a lot of strength.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the sake of learning, I have been thinking that we should be able to relate the disaster taking place on March 11, 2011 at 14.46 pm to its corresponding Bazi, ZWDS chart, and Yijing hexagram.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src='/images/sendai-bazi.png' alt='alt bazi' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Software credit: &lt;a href='http://www.mybazi.com/plotchart/4p.php'&gt;mybazi.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the above Bazi chart, each pillar has either the heavenly stem countering the earthly branch, or the other way around. From left to right: the Ji earth in Wei counters the Gui water at the heavenly stem, Yi wood counters the earth in Chou, Xin metal counters the Yi wood in Mao. Moreover, there&amp;#8217;s a repetition (fuyin) between month and year pillar. Although a Fuyin doesn&amp;#8217;t necessarily denote a bad event, it is obvious how bad it was in this instance. The bazi of the event is also extremely Yin. There is no presence of Yang element at all, even at the hidden stems inside the branches. There is Chou-Wei clash that took place between the hour and day pillar, and both involved the same element Ji, a muddy kind of earth or soil. Mao and Wei goat silent-push the Hai pig to form the wood frame, giving more twigs for the Xin metal to cut. There&amp;#8217;s a lot of tension in the air with the additional concern of nuclear radiation. In terms of 10 Gods, all the elements in the bazi appear to be unconventional deities. They tend to be sneaky and love to throw suprises&amp;#8230; Seven Killings are also dominant in the chart. The nature of the disaster is quick and aggresive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notice the Ren Wu at conception pillar. With water above fire and countering each other, it is a pillar that denotes explosiveness and sudden changes in outcomes. Since there are different schools of Bazi, I shall stop my Bazi perspective here &amp;#8211; unless it&amp;#8217;s justified to make use of the Wu horse at the conception pillar. If this is indeed the case, we may be able to take harm, destruction, and half bullying punishment into account. But still, we don&amp;#8217;t know which one will have priority over another. Fire is produced when Wu and Wei combined, and we have seen there&amp;#8217;s fire everywhere after the event. The Chou-Wu harm along with the Mao-Wu destruction involving the Eating God are telltale sign that the country&amp;#8217;s performance is affected (in economical sense). In addition to the lost of available properties (indirect wealth), their capacity for generating new wealth will be hindered for a while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src='/images/hex51.png' alt='alt yijing' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Software credit: &lt;a href='http://fivearts.net'&gt;Benjimen via FiveArts.net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using the Plum Blossom numerology or Mei Hua Yi Su, the time and date of the event is represented by &lt;strong&gt;Hexagram 51, Zhen&lt;/strong&gt;. It is an image of thunder above thunder. There are repeated shocks and tremble, which is what an earthquake is all about. It can be seen as a period of anxiousness, followed by the time to reflect and get in touch with the universe and cosmic forces. The changing line at line 6 brings us to relating Hexagram 21: Fire above thunder. When the law of nature is defied, there&amp;#8217;s payback to enforce the law.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The shock is twining, twining, looking around in terror, terror. To set things right: pitfall. The shock does not reach oneself; it reaches one&amp;#8217;s neighbor, no fault. A marriage brings talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think a natural disaster of this scale always has something to teach all of us, just like the big tsunami that happened in Aceh at the end of 2004. There has been so much taken for granted, as well as exploited from whatever the nature can give. In return, we should show some compassion and use the resources wisely &amp;#8211; one of the many ways to prepare for the future even though one is not affected directly by the disaster. Be more realistic, think further ahead, and prepare always for the uncommon and unexpected. It does not look like the recovery and rebuilding process will be an easy one. Hexagram 39 shows obstruction, but with great determination they will overcome it. It is an image of water above mountain, limping. Extraordinary measures are likely to be taken, just like what have been seeing from the nuclear plant workers &amp;#8211; &lt;code&gt;The noble one reverses his being to repair the character&lt;/code&gt;. Diligence and persistence will be the key as they can&amp;#8217;t rely merely on external support. The good news is that people of Japan have been helping themselves and taking care of each other. Regardless, I hope that they can still make use of the donation and foreign&amp;#8217;s financial help to speed up the recovery and their citizens can slowly get their life back on track.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coincidentally, in one of the blogs I followed, the writer has long foreseen that a big earthquake was going to happen. Check out his blog entries on &lt;a href='http://atouchofancientszhouyi.blogspot.com/2010_02_01_archive.html'&gt;February 28, 2010&lt;/a&gt; and on &lt;a href='http://atouchofancientszhouyi.blogspot.com/2010/05/can-mountain-withstand-shocks.html'&gt;May 5, 2010&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src='/images/ziwei-march11.png' alt='alt zwds' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;#8217;s give another try from Zi Wei Dou Shu perspective &lt;sup id='fnref:1'&gt;&lt;a href='#fn:1' rel='footnote'&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. First, take a look at the travel palace. Using 4 hua or dynamic flying star, the &lt;strong&gt;travel palace is clashed&lt;/strong&gt;. The Bing stem at Self domain flies hua ji to Lian Zhen at the travel domain. Lianzhen the Passion Star is also one of the two major Stars that present the widest difference when it is attached with Huaji the Negative Enhancer 化忌.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;sickness palace&lt;/strong&gt; that gives indication of the state of health and emotional health is best to be left empty. In this palace, there&amp;#8217;s Wen Chang with birth Hua Ji and life palace Hua Ke to Wen Chang. The negative effect of Hua ji, that brings obstructive energy and represents the extreme, is enhanced by the Hua Ke. Not to mention the Xin stem also self Hua Ji. At the health 3 Positions 4 Cardinals (San Fang Si Zheng, abbreviated as SFSZ), this birth Hua Ji meets Lu at parents palace, Quan at siblings place, and Ke at estate palace. These 3 multiplers altogether serve to reinforce the Hua Ji energy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is always a relationship between one domain and its sixth domain. Counting counterclockwise, the sixth domain of travel palace falls on the parents palace. Since the &lt;strong&gt;parents palace&lt;/strong&gt; is directly opposite the health palace, it represents the exterior health. The Ding stem makes this palace self Hua Ji. In addition, it receives Hua Ji and Hua Ke from the Karma palace which represents the unconscious, indirect wealth. The Karma palace also happens to be the sixth domain of Health palace. It sends Hua Quan power multiplier to the sibling palace. Note that the &lt;strong&gt;sibling palace&lt;/strong&gt; is the SFSZ OF both estate and health palace. Tai Yin and Tai Yang at sibling palace is self Hua Ji and Hua Ji again from the spouse palace. Opposite the sibling palace is the friends palace. The Xin stem resides at the friends palace. It also shares the same stem with the health palace. On top of the Hua Ji effect, the absence of major stars at friend palace may indicate the lost of loved ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another sign is Wen Qu self Hua Ji at the estate palace, coupled with Wen Chang birth and self Hua Ji at the health palace (mentioned above). Po Jun at the related wealth palace denotes exhaustion and lost of properties. The impatience character of Tan Lang and unseen Tuo Luo effect are boosted by Hua Lu and Hua Quan received from the Karma palace and Estate palace respectively. Tuo luo is found just across the clashed travel palace. With Tan Lang meeting Huo Xing at life SFSZ, this shows the sudden characteristic of the event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, we can draw connection to the Tsunami from both Tan Lang and Lian Zhen having the water element. Out of 12 domains, the most problematic domains are the travel and health domains that collectively affect the rest of the domains. As seen above, both parents and sibling domains affect the health domain to a big extent. Health and sibling palace subsequently affect the friends palace, depicting a helpless situation. Most of us will think it is useless to do reverse-engineering to the event that has already happened. But we can still gather the signs and use them to help prepare ourselves better for the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class='footnotes'&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li id='fn:1'&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are great learning materials at &lt;a href='http://fengshuiforward.com/forum/'&gt;Fengshui Forward forum discussion&lt;/a&gt; and their &lt;a href='http://www.facebook.com/#!/group.php?gid=128356577191615'&gt;ZWDS group&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href='#fnref:1' rev='footnote'&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>In Search of Catalyst for Getting Things Done</title>
   <link href="http://www.rue-tuscany.com/well-being/facts/motivation.html"/>
   <updated>2011-03-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>id:/well-being/facts/motivation</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Everyone will be happy if I can be done with my thesis. Needless to say, I will be the happiest if I can live up to my aspirations. I have contemplated using the carrot and stick approach to keep myself going, setting time line for each small task. It hasn&amp;#8217;t worked quite well because I&amp;#8217;ve always managed to get tied down to some distraction, and another week passes by just like that. It&amp;#8217;s scary to think about it at times. In his &lt;a href='http://www.happenchance.net/'&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt;, Seth mentioned that the environment has to be supportive and you need the right trigger for behavioral change. I don&amp;#8217;t have the first, because I prefer to work from home and I&amp;#8217;m saving money for the better things I could easily have at home &amp;#8211; eating out is expensive and the quality is not so good at any universities. I&amp;#8217;m not doing what is best, and I miss the time when I could talk to my friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, I have been figuring out how to minimize noise to my workspace. Listening to music with headphones on is not the good answer all the time, because it can easily turn into another distraction itself. As for the trigger, there could have been so much potential coming from inside the more you reflect about things. My advisor has been wonderful and supportive. I simply haven&amp;#8217;t pushed myself hard enough as an adult. I think I need to set standards and be strict with them. Furthermore, &lt;a href='http://www.happenchance.net/6-reasons-why-behavior-change-is-hard%E2%80%A6and-how-to-make-it-easier/'&gt;fear and guilt-based motivator&lt;/a&gt; will not work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My current motivators are: 1) So that I could regain my self confidence by finishing graduate school. 2) I won&amp;#8217;t ruin the good relationship with my advisor. Wouldn&amp;#8217;t it be more exciting to possibly stretch those into long term, lasting goals?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I love the potential use and awesomeness of the things I&amp;#8217;m working on, I haven&amp;#8217;t put my heart and energy 100% in it. When the only goal you have in mind is to graduate, and you don&amp;#8217;t even know where you will be living next, and whether you will be able to find a job related to your field thereafter, things do not sound so promising. While I&amp;#8217;m looking forward to finding out what will be in store for me, I&amp;#8217;m afraid to lose the flexibility and freedom I have in graduate school. Perhaps I just need an assurance that I will be working on great things next. Unfortunately, good things seldom come without hard work. There&amp;#8217;s no shortcut&amp;#8230; . I&amp;#8217;m still searching for the higher purpose that will stand the test of time to keep me motivated in whatever responsibilities I choose to bear, and I found this inspiring talk from &lt;a href='http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=u6XAPnuFjJc'&gt;Dan Pink&amp;#8217;s talk at the RSA&lt;/a&gt;. Let me give a short summary of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is common knowledge that human beings perform their best under the premise of big rewards or incentives. But there&amp;#8217;s another model known as the &amp;#8216;left wing&amp;#8217; or &amp;#8216;socialist&amp;#8217; reward that we may not hear much of. Some may consider that as strange economic behavior. When people are assigned tasks that require above rudimentary cognitive skill &amp;#8211; those more than just basic tasks following along a set of algorithmic rules &amp;#8211; which require some conceptual, creative thinking, study shows that higher incentives lead to poorer performances. Why is that so? People are purpose maximizer, and they want to be self-directed; all of us need a sense of purpose. More and more organizations want to have some kind of transcendent purpose. When the profit motive gets unmoored from the purpose motive, bad things happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of people have full time job with limited discretionary time, yet they still find time to volunteer unconditionally. Similary, we see many of those who play instruments just for fun during the weekends. This proves that challenge to mastery makes contribution. Another great example is of the Australian-based software company, Atlassian. One day, the company decided to let its employees to work on anything they love for the next 24 hours &amp;#8211; under the condition that they had to report the result at the end of the day. Unexpectedly, the employees produced great fixes that otherwise will never emerge under normal cicumstances. When we treat people like people, we make a better world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have time, watching the video is much better. I tried to recapture the talk although it&amp;#8217;s been a few days since I watched it. The 10.38 min video has wonderful illustration and narrative.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Patience</title>
   <link href="http://www.rue-tuscany.com/website/random/patience.html"/>
   <updated>2011-03-04T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>id:/website/random/patience</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As of last week, I found myself improving minor aspects of this site that have no importance at all. I was simply bored. When I noticed that &lt;a href='http://bit.ly/pro/products'&gt;bit.ly pro beta&lt;/a&gt; was free, I became interested to give it a try. I thought it would take at most an hour for the setup and I&amp;#8217;d have my custom short url. But I only realized it later that we need to already own the custom short domain - since it&amp;#8217;s no longer a short domain if I use the subdomain of rue-tuscany. Names I could think of were already taken with the desired tld (other than .com, .org, .net, .info, .me, etc). My first choice was et.sy. It was available, but is considered too short to my disappointment. &lt;a href='www.eurodns.com'&gt;Eurodns&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href='http://domai.nr'&gt;domai.nr&lt;/a&gt; have helped the most in reaching the final decision with &lt;a href='http://prata.es'&gt;prata.es&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; &lt;a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roti_prata'&gt;roti prata&lt;/a&gt; which I haven&amp;#8217;t had for years :-).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The setup obviously took more than an hour although the steps were straightforward. It was hard to think clearly of what stopped it from working properly at the beginning. And I told myself it would be wise to give up trying as it&amp;#8217;s not necessary to use your own short url, especially when the default ones from bit.ly or j.mp can be even shorter than mine. Another consideration was the fact that a domain name purchase typically comes together with the purchase of web hosting. Spending $7 per month for Zerigo DNS upgrade may not be such a good idea when you don&amp;#8217;t have 10 different domains to manage. It was nice knowing that we can use the default nameservers from the domain registrar, thus eliminating the need for the web hosting. Setting A record to point to the IP address specified by bit.ly was the key. I was happy when I thought I was done, until I realize I still had a parked short custom domain a few days later. No wonder I kept getting a broken link upon shortening my post urls. Removing a bunch of other dns records and leaving only the A record pointed to bit.ly fixed the problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, I can&amp;#8217;t believe I ended up getting my own short domain, which may be construed as being done for vanity reason. I learned that I became less patient and worry prone when I had been stealing time supposedly spent on my thesis. At the same time, it made me realize that there are many things that require patience. For example, everytime we buy a new domain, nameservers take time to propagate across the web. When things do not work properly, it is not always due to your technical shortcomings. It&amp;#8217;s worth the wait while assuming responsibilities of the other high priority task, because if we have reviewed everything from our end, the rest will usually take care of themselves. It will help us allocate our mental resources better if we know when to avoid unnecessary worries. This reminds me of how I used to panic when I need the internet during its down time. Attempting to fix it didn&amp;#8217;t overcome the problem because there&amp;#8217;s nothing wrong with both the modem and phone line. How can we solve the problem when we have no control over the entire resources? This brings a flashback of my time working at the support desk six years ago.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Starting Over</title>
   <link href="http://www.rue-tuscany.com/website/starting-over.html"/>
   <updated>2011-02-28T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>id:/website/starting-over</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This site used to be hosted on &lt;a href='http://hostingrails.com/'&gt;HostingRails&lt;/a&gt;, and have since used two different domain names: rosebery.ca, miffytrail.com. The main reason for recent domain name switches was simply because I did not find the name truly resonated with me. I wish I could have used my full name, but that will be utterly impossible, given how many Jennifer Lee(s) are out there&amp;#8230; Hence, a blog redesign, and the name &amp;#8216;rue-tuscany&amp;#8217; a.k.a &amp;#8216;Train of Thoughts to Tuscany&amp;#8217;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have experienced difficulty in keeping up a regular blog, so my apology to those who stopped by this site last year. Blogging at least once per week would be the most to expect for now. But again, don&amp;#8217;t take my words for it. My cognitive ability has somewhat decreased since my graduate courses were completed over a year ago. Thinking that I could focus solely on my master thesis, and therefore postponed looking for jobs does not really work out for me. Perhaps it&amp;#8217;s time to admit I no longer have the capacity to engage in research intensive types of project, or that I failed to be passionate enough in what I&amp;#8217;m doing. Taking that into account, it will be reasonable to save money for the hosting. &lt;a href='http://heroku.com/'&gt;Heroku&lt;/a&gt; came in just at the right time to host this site for free. A very good explanation on how to set it up to work with Jekyll can be found at this &lt;a href='http://datamangling.com/2010/07/Jekyll-on-Heroku'&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 
</feed>
