<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>Train of Thoughts to Tuscany</title>
 <link href="http://www.rue-tuscany.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://www.rue-tuscany.com"/>
 <updated>2011-04-09T19:44:58-04:00</updated>
 <id>http://www.rue-tuscany.com/</id>
 <author>
   <name>Jennifer Lee</name>
   <email>leecarrot@gmail.com</email>
 </author>
 
 
 <entry>
   <title>Nexus S</title>
   <link href="http://www.rue-tuscany.com/random/nexus-s.html"/>
   <updated>2011-04-09T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>id:/random/nexus-s</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I am overwhelmed with my spendings over the last two months. Back in February, I bought the original Office 2010 suite, Adobe Acrobat Reader Pro, Adobe Design Standard which includes Adobe Illustrator and Photoshop CS5. They are still expensive even though I went with the educational versions at distinctly reduced prices after submitting my university identification. A month later, I traded up my Olympus EPL-1 micro four-third camera for the Canon EOS 60D with 18-200 mm EF/IS lens (with image stabilizer and Hoya lens protector) in the hope to learn the manual settings of a DSLR.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am starting to get more comfortable with my camera. I posted some pictures &lt;a href='http://www.flickr.com/photos/16714744@N06/'&gt;on Flickr&lt;/a&gt; and I have a long way to go to get desired shots :). It&amp;#8217;s worth the money overall. Aside from having the opportunity to start learning some serious photography, I also get to be exposed to editing with Photoshop and Illustrator. All within the comfort of knowing I can keep these software for an infinite time without the annoyance that usually comes with illegitimate software. Now that the right tools are on my hands, I should be ready to go creative and get busy. I love flexibility and sudden insights, and hope to continue to grow new perspectives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then came this idea of having a mutipurpose device that can fit nicely in my pocket. For a long time, I was pretty convinced that I wouldn&amp;#8217;t need a smart phone. I got my iPad 1 in June 2010, and I&amp;#8217;ve been enjoying it ever since. It&amp;#8217;s particularly useful for all my readings. I have been able to gradually reduce paper and ink usage from the use of my laser printer. My 2005 Nokia mobile phone will do the job during emergencies. It was only recently that the mobile plan is starting to get the most out of me. &lt;p&gt;Even though I went with the $10 prepaid plan, I had received telemarketing calls whenever the phone was on. Moreover, they ate up my minutes simply from the incoming calls, resulting in the $10 refill amount became insufficient to make calls sometimes. When I forgot to refill on the expiry date -- which is usually a month later -- I lost my existing balance. This has happened too often, but I was too lazy to look for a better solution. Not to mention the accumulated Fido dollars/rewards are unusable. Perhaps there is a way to block these telemarketing numbers, or there aren't any. Another way out is to get a new activation with Fido again. But I have an option not to stick with Fido, equivalent to not spending my money on a carrier that usually goes together with the Big 3 when there is now an emerging no contract, no hidden fees carriers in Canada. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So for more than two weeks now, my old cell phone has 5 cents remaining even though I haven&amp;#8217;t made any outgoing calls since the refill a month ago. I have no one to call, and I haven&amp;#8217;t encountered any difficulty on the road while driving. Although I had been able to live without a mobile phone, things can go unpredictable anytime and I definitely need to bring one with me just in case. I&amp;#8217;ve been considering to use my iPad with the &lt;a href='http://shop.windmobile.ca/ProductCatalog/Handsets/DatastickDetails.aspx?id=Huawei+E583%28WINDCA%29&amp;amp;color=blue'&gt;Windspeed Pocket Hotspot&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;#8217;s a Mifi that can serve as wireless hotspot for up to five other devices including laptop and the iPad. This way, I would then only need to sign up for a (possibly unlimited) data plan without the default talk and text plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plan was to use Skype for taking and receiving calls. It&amp;#8217;s not such an ideal solution, because Canada does not have online Skype number yet, which means that whenever people call me in Ottawa, they will actually call the US number in Ogdensburg, New York, instead of the local number. That will certainly cost more for them, but it may work if it&amp;#8217;s a short phone call and I call them back later. If not for the Android 2.3 Gingerbread platform (means one of the first to get update from Google), cleanliness and the ease of customization in Nexus S, instant camera (to take with me when going for a walk and driving) &amp;#8211; and the size of a smart/mobile phone &amp;#8211; using the combination of Skype, Mifi and iPad is much less expensive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the same time, Nexus S was only two weeks away from its official release in Canada. Two weeks later, I&amp;#8217;m really succumbing to temptation. I spent a lot of time debating with myself whether to get one or not. I decided in order to get back to work, I should just get one so I won&amp;#8217;t spend too much time mulling over it. Next time faced with similar dilemma, I have to remind myself to read Pysblog: &lt;a href='http://www.spring.org.uk/2011/04/top-10-self-control-strategies.php'&gt;Top Ten Self-Control Strategies&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src='/images/nexus_s-complete.jpg' alt='alt nexus' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Nexus One was released, I already fell in love with Google phone featuring Android OS, but I managed to resist getting one for myself last year, nor did I rush to get an iPhone 3GS or 4. With the exeception for iPad as an eReader, I was not sold at all with iPhone or iPod touch. But this year is quite different. For some reason, our wireless provider &amp;#8211; Primus Telecommunication &amp;#8211; has been blocking some websites, possibly of UK origin for almost a half year. From experience, it&amp;#8217;s hard to get them fixed it right away because they would waste your time troubleshooting unrelated things. This is unbeliavable. Since I work from home mostly, I need to test out whether the website is really down, or it actually works with other providers. I figured I could do it if I had an alternative internet connection, such as 3G. &lt;p&gt; I went to get my Nexus S yesterday afternoon. It is $25 more expensive at WindMobile, but it is still a decent price. Videotron in Quebec was the first to sell Nexus S in Canada globally. But some people had been getting the phone from Wind the day before. The news was reliable and I took the chance to visit the retailer. They have actually begun selling it even though it was listed as coming soon on their website. I will see if I can have a price adjustment if they reduce the price within the next 14 days to keep up with the competition. I was advised to go with the $45 unstoppable plan, but I didn't. It was a difficult decision. I need to test out if the $10 Social Mobile data add-on works for me. I wish there was an option to eliminate the default voice plan. I currently go with the $15, but I'm sure I'll have a lot of unused minutes :). I was told that if we go with the $20 data add-on, the total cost including voice plan and after taxes will be very close to $45. But I'm still not convinced. $45 after taxes will be more than $50. I just have to see for myself. Within a limited time, I will be able to upgrade if I need to. The total monthly payment is $25 for now. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src='/images/nexus_s-side.jpg' alt='alt nexus' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Google Phone is supposed to be unlocked, but I don't know why they told me I can only unlock it after three months with Wind. I really need someone to confirm this. Koodo Mobile has really an attractive price at $425, $75 less expensive than others. If you go on tab, you only need to pay $275 and put the remaining amount on tab. Simply settle the outstanding balance when leaving and you can keep the phone. The tab plan may be just slightly better than a contract. They may have other ways to make profit. Besides, is the phone going to work with foreign SIM cards if I leave Canada? They had one at Best Buy yesterday, but I couldn't buy the phone outright. Instead, I would need to sign a 3 year contract for new activation with Fido. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src='/images/nexus_s-back.jpg' alt='alt nexus' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Gedit as All Purpose Text Editor and IDE</title>
   <link href="http://www.rue-tuscany.com/productivity/gedit.html"/>
   <updated>2011-04-07T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>id:/productivity/gedit</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I had been checking out Emacs. I heard a lot of good things about both Emacs and Vim. I wish I was a quick learner. Due to the time constrain and learning curve, I decided to continue using Gedit for the time being. It doesn&amp;#8217;t make a tremendeous difference whether I use Gedit or other editors, as long as I get things done. I will definitely try to pick up Emacs again in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gedit is quite a decent text editor and IDE in my opinion. The main thing that I really like about gedit is its simplicity and ease of use. It is a default editor that comes with Gnome. I recently reinstalled Latex plugin after upgrading to Ubuntu 10.10. I have also activated a number of plugins such as the Word Completion, Align for columns. I am also using it as a Python IDE. &lt;em&gt;Code Highlighting, Bracket completion, Class Browser, Embedded Terminal, Python Code Completion, Python Indentation and Better Python Console&lt;/em&gt; are among plugins that may help obtain as much seamless coding experience as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src='/images/gedit.png' alt='alt gedit' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wrote a simple Python script to make sure plugins were working properly for the first time. At a later time, who knows I needed a random number generator to decide on the mobile carrier since I don&amp;#8217;t know which plans are suitable for the Nexus S I&amp;#8217;m getting next week :-).&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Tsunami and Earthquake</title>
   <link href="http://www.rue-tuscany.com/random/astrology/japan-earthquake.html"/>
   <updated>2011-03-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>id:/random/astrology/japan-earthquake</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My heart goes out to the people of Japan dealing with the aftermath of earthquake and tsunami. May all the life lost can peacefully continue their journey to the next stage. I admire those working at the nuclear plants, and I wish them well. I believe the people of Japan will come out of this with a lot of strength.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the sake of learning, I have been thinking that we should be able to relate the disaster taking place on March 11, 2011 at 14.46 pm to its corresponding Bazi, ZWDS chart, and Yijing hexagram.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src='/images/sendai-bazi.png' alt='alt bazi' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Software credit: &lt;a href='http://www.mybazi.com/plotchart/4p.php'&gt;mybazi.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the above Bazi chart, each pillar has either the heavenly stem countering the earthly branch, or the other way around. From left to right: the Ji earth in Wei counters the Gui water at the heavenly stem, Yi wood counters the earth in Chou, Xin metal counters the Yi wood in Mao. Moreover, there&amp;#8217;s a repetition (fuyin) between month and year pillar. Although a Fuyin doesn&amp;#8217;t necessarily denote a bad event, it is obvious how bad it was in this instance. The bazi of the event is also extremely Yin. There is no presence of Yang element at all, even at the hidden stems inside the branches. There is Chou-Wei clash that took place between the hour and day pillar, and both involved the same element Ji, a muddy kind of earth or soil. Mao and Wei goat silent-push the Hai pig to form the wood frame, giving more twigs for the Xin metal to cut. There&amp;#8217;s a lot of tension in the air with the additional concern of nuclear radiation. In terms of 10 Gods, all the elements in the bazi appear to be unconventional deities. They tend to be sneaky and love to throw suprises&amp;#8230; Seven Killings are also dominant in the chart. The nature of the disaster is quick and aggresive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notice the Ren Wu at conception pillar. With water above fire and countering each other, it is a pillar that denotes explosiveness and sudden changes in outcomes. Since there are different schools of Bazi, I shall stop my Bazi perspective here &amp;#8211; unless it&amp;#8217;s justified to make use of the Wu horse at the conception pillar. If this is indeed the case, we may be able to take harm, destruction, and half bullying punishment into account. But still, we don&amp;#8217;t know which one will have priority over another. Fire is produced when Wu and Wei combined, and we have seen there&amp;#8217;s fire everywhere after the event. The Chou-Wu harm along with the Mao-Wu destruction involving the Eating God are telltale sign that the country&amp;#8217;s performance is affected (in economical sense). In addition to the lost of available properties (indirect wealth), their capacity for generating new wealth will be hindered for a while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src='/images/hex51.png' alt='alt yijing' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Software credit: &lt;a href='http://fivearts.net'&gt;Benjimen via FiveArts.net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using the Plum Blossom numerology or Mei Hua Yi Su, the time and date of the event is represented by &lt;strong&gt;Hexagram 51, Zhen&lt;/strong&gt;. It is an image of thunder above thunder. There are repeated shocks and tremble, which is what an earthquake is all about. It can be seen as a period of anxiousness, followed by the time to reflect and get in touch with the universe and cosmic forces. The changing line at line 6 brings us to relating Hexagram 21: Fire above thunder. When the law of nature is defied, there&amp;#8217;s payback to enforce the law.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The shock is twining, twining, looking around in terror, terror. To set things right: pitfall. The shock does not reach oneself; it reaches one&amp;#8217;s neighbor, no fault. A marriage brings talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think a natural disaster of this scale always has something to teach all of us, just like the big tsunami that happened in Aceh at the end of 2004. There has been so much taken for granted, as well as exploited from whatever the nature can give. In return, we should show some compassion and use the resources wisely &amp;#8211; one of the many ways to prepare for the future even though one is not affected directly by the disaster. Be more realistic, think further ahead, and prepare always for the uncommon and unexpected. It does not look like the recovery and rebuilding process will be an easy one. Hexagram 39 shows obstruction, but with great determination they will overcome it. It is an image of water above mountain, limping. Extraordinary measures are likely to be taken, just like what have been seeing from the nuclear plant workers &amp;#8211; &lt;code&gt;The noble one reverses his being to repair the character&lt;/code&gt;. Diligence and persistence will be the key as they can&amp;#8217;t rely merely on external support. The good news is that people of Japan have been helping themselves and taking care of each other. Regardless, I hope that they can still make use of the donation and foreign&amp;#8217;s financial help to speed up the recovery and their citizens can slowly get their life back on track.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coincidentally, in one of the blogs I followed, the writer has long foreseen that a big earthquake was going to happen. Check out his blog entries on &lt;a href='http://atouchofancientszhouyi.blogspot.com/2010_02_01_archive.html'&gt;February 28, 2010&lt;/a&gt; and on &lt;a href='http://atouchofancientszhouyi.blogspot.com/2010/05/can-mountain-withstand-shocks.html'&gt;May 5, 2010&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src='/images/ziwei-march11.png' alt='alt zwds' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;#8217;s give another try from Zi Wei Dou Shu perspective &lt;sup id='fnref:1'&gt;&lt;a href='#fn:1' rel='footnote'&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. First, take a look at the travel palace. Using 4 hua or dynamic flying star, the &lt;strong&gt;travel palace is clashed&lt;/strong&gt;. The Bing stem at Self domain flies hua ji to Lian Zhen at the travel domain. Lianzhen the Passion Star is also one of the two major Stars that present the widest difference when it is attached with Huaji the Negative Enhancer 化忌.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;sickness palace&lt;/strong&gt; that gives indication of the state of health and emotional health is best to be left empty. In this palace, there&amp;#8217;s Wen Chang with birth Hua Ji and life palace Hua Ke to Wen Chang. The negative effect of Hua ji, that brings obstructive energy and represents the extreme, is enhanced by the Hua Ke. Not to mention the Xin stem also self Hua Ji. At the health 3 Positions 4 Cardinals (San Fang Si Zheng, abbreviated as SFSZ), this birth Hua Ji meets Lu at parents palace, Quan at siblings place, and Ke at estate palace. These 3 multiplers altogether serve to reinforce the Hua Ji energy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is always a relationship between one domain and its sixth domain. Counting counterclockwise, the sixth domain of travel palace falls on the parents palace. Since the &lt;strong&gt;parents palace&lt;/strong&gt; is directly opposite the health palace, it represents the exterior health. The Ding stem makes this palace self Hua Ji. In addition, it receives Hua Ji and Hua Ke from the Karma palace which represents the unconscious, indirect wealth. The Karma palace also happens to be the sixth domain of Health palace. It sends Hua Quan power multiplier to the sibling palace. Note that the &lt;strong&gt;sibling palace&lt;/strong&gt; is the SFSZ OF both estate and health palace. Tai Yin and Tai Yang at sibling palace is self Hua Ji and Hua Ji again from the spouse palace. Opposite the sibling palace is the friends palace. The Xin stem resides at the friends palace. It also shares the same stem with the health palace. On top of the Hua Ji effect, the absence of major stars at friend palace may indicate the lost of loved ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another sign is Wen Qu self Hua Ji at the estate palace, coupled with Wen Chang birth and self Hua Ji at the health palace (mentioned above). Po Jun at the related wealth palace denotes exhaustion and lost of properties. The impatience character of Tan Lang and unseen Tuo Luo effect are boosted by Hua Lu and Hua Quan received from the Karma palace and Estate palace respectively. Tuo luo is found just across the clashed travel palace. With Tan Lang meeting Huo Xing at life SFSZ, this shows the sudden characteristic of the event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, we can draw connection to the Tsunami from both Tan Lang and Lian Zhen having the water element. Out of 12 domains, the most problematic domains are the travel and health domains that collectively affect the rest of the domains. As seen above, both parents and sibling domains affect the health domain to a big extent. Health and sibling palace subsequently affect the friends palace, depicting a helpless situation. Most of us will think it is useless to do reverse-engineering to the event that has already happened. But we can still gather the signs and use them to help prepare ourselves better for the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class='footnotes'&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li id='fn:1'&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are great learning materials at &lt;a href='http://fengshuiforward.com/forum/'&gt;Fengshui Forward forum discussion&lt;/a&gt; and their &lt;a href='http://www.facebook.com/#!/group.php?gid=128356577191615'&gt;ZWDS group&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href='#fnref:1' rev='footnote'&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>In Search of Catalyst for Getting Things Done</title>
   <link href="http://www.rue-tuscany.com/well-being/facts/motivation.html"/>
   <updated>2011-03-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>id:/well-being/facts/motivation</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I always tell myself to finish my thesis so that I can move on. Yes, everyone will be happy if I can be done with it. I have contemplated using the carrot and stick approach to keep myself going, setting time line for each small task. It hasn&amp;#8217;t worked quite well because I&amp;#8217;ve always managed to get tied down to some distraction, and another week passes by just like that. It&amp;#8217;s scary to think about it at times. In his &lt;a href='http://www.happenchance.net/'&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt;, Seth mentioned that the environment has to be supportive and you need the right trigger for behavioral change. I don&amp;#8217;t have the first, because I prefer to work from home and I&amp;#8217;m saving money for the better things I could easily have at home &amp;#8211; eating out is expensive and the quality is not so good at any universities. I&amp;#8217;m not doing what is best, and I miss the time when I could talk to my friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, I have been figuring out how to minimize noise to my workspace. Listening to music with headphones on is not the good answer all the time, because it can easily turn into another distraction itself. As for the trigger, there could have been so much potential coming from inside the more you reflect about things. My advisor has been wonderful and supportive. I simply haven&amp;#8217;t pushed myself hard enough as an adult. I think I need to set standards and be strict with them. Furthermore, &lt;a href='http://www.happenchance.net/6-reasons-why-behavior-change-is-hard%E2%80%A6and-how-to-make-it-easier/'&gt;fear and guilt-based motivator&lt;/a&gt; will not work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My current motivators are: 1) So that I could regain my self confidence by finishing graduate school. 2) I won&amp;#8217;t ruin the good relationship with my advisor. Wouldn&amp;#8217;t it be more exciting to possibly stretch those into long term, lasting goals?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I love the potential use and awesomeness of the things I&amp;#8217;m working on, I haven&amp;#8217;t put my heart and energy 100% in it. When the only goal you have in mind is to graduate, and you don&amp;#8217;t even know where you will be living next, and whether you will be able to find a job related to your field thereafter, things do not sound so promising. While I&amp;#8217;m looking forward to finding out what will be in store for me, I&amp;#8217;m afraid to lose the flexibility and freedom I have in graduate school. Perhaps I just need an assurance that I will be working on great things next. Unfortunately, good things seldom come without hard work. There&amp;#8217;s no shortcut&amp;#8230; . I&amp;#8217;m still searching for the higher purpose that will stand the test of time to keep me motivated in whatever responsibilities I choose to bear, and I found this inspiring talk from &lt;a href='http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=u6XAPnuFjJc'&gt;Dan Pink&amp;#8217;s talk at the RSA&lt;/a&gt;. Let me give a short summary of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is common knowledge that human beings perform their best under the premise of big rewards or incentives. But there&amp;#8217;s another model known as the &amp;#8216;left wing&amp;#8217; or &amp;#8216;socialist&amp;#8217; reward that we may not hear much of. Some may consider that as strange economic behavior. When people are assigned tasks that require above rudimentary cognitive skill &amp;#8211; those more than just basic tasks following along a set of algorithmic rules &amp;#8211; which require some conceptual, creative thinking, study shows that higher incentives lead to poorer performances. Why is that so? People are purpose maximizer, and they want to be self-directed; all of us need a sense of purpose. More and more organizations want to have some kind of transcendent purpose. When the profit motive gets unmoored from the purpose motive, bad things happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of people have full time job with limited discretionary time, yet they still find time to volunteer unconditionally. Similary, we see many of those who play instruments just for fun during the weekends. This proves that challenge to mastery makes contribution. Another great example is of the Australian-based software company, Atlassian. One day, the company decided to let its employees to work on anything they love for the next 24 hours &amp;#8211; under the condition that they had to report the result at the end of the day. Unexpectedly, the employees produced great fixes that otherwise will never emerge under normal cicumstances. When we treat people like people, we make a better world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have time, watching the video is much better. I tried to recapture the talk although it&amp;#8217;s been a few days since I watched it. The 10.38 min video has wonderful illustration and narrative.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Patience</title>
   <link href="http://www.rue-tuscany.com/website/random/patience.html"/>
   <updated>2011-03-04T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>id:/website/random/patience</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As of last week, I found myself improving minor aspects of this site that have no importance at all. I was simply bored. When I noticed that &lt;a href='http://bit.ly/pro/products'&gt;bit.ly pro beta&lt;/a&gt; was free, I became interested to give it a try. I thought it would take at most an hour for the setup and I&amp;#8217;d have my custom short url. But I only realized it later that we need to already own the custom short domain - since it&amp;#8217;s no longer a short domain if I use the subdomain of rue-tuscany. Names I could think of were already taken with the desired tld (other than .com, .org, .net, .info, .me, etc). My first choice was et.sy. It was available, but is considered too short to my disappointment. &lt;a href='www.eurodns.com'&gt;Eurodns&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href='http://domai.nr'&gt;domai.nr&lt;/a&gt; have helped the most in reaching the final decision with &lt;a href='http://prata.es'&gt;prata.es&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; &lt;a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roti_prata'&gt;roti prata&lt;/a&gt; which I haven&amp;#8217;t had for years :-).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The setup obviously took more than an hour although the steps were straightforward. It was hard to think clearly of what stopped it from working properly at the beginning. And I told myself it would be wise to give up trying as it&amp;#8217;s not necessary to use your own short url, especially when the default ones from bit.ly or j.mp can be even shorter than mine. Another consideration was the fact that a domain name purchase typically comes together with the purchase of web hosting. Spending $7 per month for Zerigo DNS upgrade may not be such a good idea when you don&amp;#8217;t have 10 different domains to manage. It was nice knowing that we can use the default nameservers from the domain registrar, thus eliminating the need for the web hosting. Setting A record to point to the IP address specified by bit.ly was the key. I was happy when I thought I was done, until I realize I still had a parked short custom domain a few days later. No wonder I kept getting a broken link upon shortening my post urls. Removing a bunch of other dns records and leaving only the A record pointed to bit.ly fixed the problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, I can&amp;#8217;t believe I ended up getting my own short domain, which may be construed as being done for vanity reason. I learned that I became less patient and worry prone when I had been stealing time supposedly spent on my thesis. At the same time, it made me realize that there are many things that require patience. For example, everytime we buy a new domain, nameservers take time to propagate across the web. When things do not work properly, it is not always due to your technical shortcomings. It&amp;#8217;s worth the wait while assuming responsibilities of the other high priority task, because if we have reviewed everything from our end, the rest will usually take care of themselves. It will help us allocate our mental resources better if we know when to avoid unnecessary worries. This reminds me of how I used to panic when I need the internet during its down time. Attempting to fix it didn&amp;#8217;t overcome the problem because there&amp;#8217;s nothing wrong with both the modem and phone line. How can we solve the problem when we have no control over the entire resources? This brings a flashback of my time working at the support desk six years ago.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Starting Over</title>
   <link href="http://www.rue-tuscany.com/website/starting-over.html"/>
   <updated>2011-02-28T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>id:/website/starting-over</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This site used to be hosted on &lt;a href='http://hostingrails.com/'&gt;HostingRails&lt;/a&gt;, and have since used two different domain names: rosebery.ca, miffytrail.com. The main reason for recent domain name switches was simply because I did not find the name truly resonated with me. I wish I could have used my full name, but that will be utterly impossible, given how many Jennifer Lee(s) are out there&amp;#8230; Hence, a blog redesign, and the name &amp;#8216;rue-tuscany&amp;#8217; a.k.a &amp;#8216;Train of Thoughts to Tuscany&amp;#8217;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have experienced difficulty in keeping up a regular blog, so my apology to those who stopped by this site last year. Blogging at least once per week would be the most to expect for now. But again, don&amp;#8217;t take my words for it. My cognitive ability has somewhat decreased since my graduate courses were completed over a year ago. Thinking that I could focus solely on my master thesis, and therefore postponed looking for jobs does not really work out for me. Perhaps it&amp;#8217;s time to admit I no longer have the capacity to engage in research intensive types of project, or that I failed to be passionate enough in what I&amp;#8217;m doing. Taking that into account, it will be reasonable to save money for the hosting. &lt;a href='http://heroku.com/'&gt;Heroku&lt;/a&gt; came in just at the right time to host this site for free. A very good explanation on how to set it up to work with Jekyll can be found at this &lt;a href='http://datamangling.com/2010/07/Jekyll-on-Heroku'&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Love and Hate Relationship with Facebook</title>
   <link href="http://www.rue-tuscany.com/privacy/facebook-privacy.html"/>
   <updated>2010-05-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>id:/privacy/facebook-privacy</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I did not persist until the end. Instead of deleting my Facebook account, I deactivated it after further consideration. Many people have come to rely on Facebook&amp;#8217;s messaging system as a practical way for easy and fast communications. However, it is not without any downside with regards to the emotional effect it brought along. There is something really wrong with excessive use that has fundamentally twisted our hopes and reality. There are many more important things awaiting us to do in the real world. I didn&amp;#8217;t regret I gave myself a break from Facebook, and I remind myself that I need not spend too much time on it if I ever reactivate it again, which I just did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After this experience, and by following closely privacy news surrounding Facebook, we ought to understand the many different viewpoints people have towards Facebook. Unfortunately, the company&amp;#8217;s stance has not changed very much despite all the complaints and pressures from privacy advocates and regulators. While the founder of Facebook thinks &lt;a href='http://www.zephoria.org/thoughts/archives/2010/05/14/facebook-and-radical-transparency-a-rant.html'&gt;radical transparency&lt;/a&gt; is good for everyone, the company does not seem to exhibit the same kind of transparency in return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, &lt;a href='http://joindiaspora.com/'&gt;Diaspora&lt;/a&gt; is a social network planned to be built as a better alternative to Facebook. It will be interesting to see how this open and decentralized network can change the game. If there is one thing that has been quite successful to keep me as a user, it will be that we don&amp;#8217;t know those people in our contact list as much as we thought we did. Once in a while, there will be random nice surprises from people who suddenly decide to get in touch, or those who express their common interest in the stuff we share. It can be felt as a kind of emotional support and warmthness.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Happy Mother's Day!</title>
   <link href="http://www.rue-tuscany.com/random/mothers-day.html"/>
   <updated>2010-05-09T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>id:/random/mothers-day</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It is now 2.57 am, and I am still figuring out some stuff for Monday. I came across this beautiful doodle from Google. I just realized it was already Mother&amp;#8217;s Day. It had been cloudy and rainy yesterday. I hope the day will soon brighthen up a bit for this occasion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I heard about Mother&amp;#8217;s Day from my little cousin just a few days ago, but I forgot when the day actually came. How sweet she was when she said my little teddy bear would have loved to prepare a gift for me, but it was unable to (as I have been like the teddy&amp;#8217;s mum). So on behalf of the teddy, she made a drawing for me. Thank you to both ^_^.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would also like to wish all the mothers in this world, a Happy Mother&amp;#8217;s Day. Thank you for all the love you have given to us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class='image_and_caption'&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img title='Happy Mother&amp;apos;s Day' src='/images/mothers-day.png' alt='mother&amp;apos;s day' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>In Pursuit of Happiness</title>
   <link href="http://www.rue-tuscany.com/well-being/happiness.html"/>
   <updated>2010-05-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>id:/well-being/happiness</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have been thinking of what it means to be really happy. Feeling as if I have been pursuing the so-called happiness relentlessly. My plans are not always carried out with full consideration beforehand, which often makes me feel guilty for failing to adhere to certain norms I set for myself. Just to be happy, I&amp;#8217;m always willing to invest in anything within my capabilities whenever deemed appropriate. This includes the monetary route as well, such as buying things and services to meet my curiosity and experimental nature. The later is more for having someone to talk to, or simply for developing a friendship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The kind of happiness obtained in such manners will not last forever. Buying physical things often falls short of our expectation, and we wake up feeling more disappointed than before. The road to happiness always foresees several wrong choices, which unfortunately are needed in order to make better-informed decision in the future. This article from &lt;a href='http://www.spring.org.uk/2010/04/six-psychological-reasons-consumer-culture-is-unsatisfying.php'&gt;Psyblog, Six Psychological Reasons Consumer Culture is Unsatisfying&lt;/a&gt; gives a nice insight to the overall implications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am still going to get things I need. Only that there is this growing tendency to think twice before purchasing things that look only attractive, but do not contain any significant values or long term benefits. I appreciate beautiful clothes. However, past lessons have taught me that I only need to replace clothes that have almost worn out. These are my favorite T-shirts, pants, or jeans, which I am happy enough to wear in different colors daily, or in slightly different styles interchangably. I used to be an avid snacker, but my health has gotten more sensitive to these food recently. I am cutting back of the amount. It will be too bad if my time is spent falling sick again from cough, throat infection, or stomach flu. These food already contain little or no nutrients. In some cases, they lead to obesity too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever I shop now, I know exactly what I need. It helps to get myself out of the stores as soon as my chores are done. All of these are simply life changes evident on the material level. On a higher level, things have never been the same since the post break-up from a four years relationship, which also happened to be my first. It has been a year and a half today without any news whatsoever. It was hard at first, but time has been my best friend. Holding no grudges, no bitterness. Does every break-up always have to lead to awkwardness, hiding, always thinking the other person is never going to be forgiving? If that is really the case, it is such a pity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I&amp;#8217;m progressing in some aspects, I have to admit my life is not as productive as what I want it to be at this moment. It feels rather empty or blend. Last year, I started to experience a symptom of withdrawal. I guess there are some side effects from always trying to find ways to heal ourselves. That&amp;#8217;s why psychologists are there for us. Nevertheless, I still believe &lt;a href='http://fengshuiforward.com/330/the-most-powerful-cure-ourselves/'&gt;the best cure is ourselves&lt;/a&gt;. The side effects I meant are the inferiority complex, analysis-paralysis, and &lt;a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Impostor_syndrome'&gt;impostor syndrome&lt;/a&gt; that I recently find myself struggling with. I think I am going to have a big trouble awaiting if I let this procrastination habit continues. I am so close to finishing my master degree, and it is just happening at this time of the year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the positive note, I have this new appreciation of being related to others. I learned the hard way the need to cherish love and true friendships, for we never know what we have until it is taken away from us. It will take some time to rebuild my connections again. And I realise it is not going to be easy, as I still find myself thinking twice as much before I act or speak. First, I need to let go of the fear or paranoia of not being liked by others at the very beginning of a friendship. I feel I have been very unfair to those whom I met briefly at graduate school. They are nice people too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class='image_and_caption'&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img title='Being Content' src='/images/contentment.png' alt='contentment' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before deleting my Facebook account, I spent a lot of time liking other people&amp;#8217;s posts, looking through their pictures and comments. I did that because I really found their stuff nice and interesting. At the same time, I also realise it is very important for everyone of us to receive any kind of appreciation or praises once in a while. There is nothing wrong if we can make someone&amp;#8217;s day better. I really do not mind doing that even though my own stuff on FB do not usually receive similar kind of interests. However, the more I do that, I will then ask myself why I have nothing better to do, or why there is such a serious lack of love and passion in my life. This has been unexpected. How easy this is turning against myself soon, and I did that a lot everyday. I think I can be very unreasonable and lacking of self control sometimes. As my number of friends are growing to more than 250, I also find the news streams are getting way too much noise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have 13 more days to go before my account is completely deleted by Facebook. It was not an easy decision even though I had spent considerable amount of time weighing the pros and cons. I have very few good friends on Facebook who uses the messaging system to keep in touch with me. There are also friends I made through Fluff Friends who can be very supportive at times. The biggest cons is clearly the fact that &lt;a href='http://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2010/04/facebook-timeline'&gt;Facebook is eroding our privacy as time goes&lt;/a&gt;. The way they do it is getting more tricky, and we as users do not have as much authority anymore. We are viewed only as their product that has a lot of valuable data to contribute in their effort to dominate the web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many who are not concerned about their privacy. But there are also those who care, and decide to just share information that is not private. They have thoroughly gone through their privacy settings. I was doing the same just before this. But I dislike Facebook&amp;#8217;s latest policy after constantly finding myself readjust the privacy settings. I also need to get away for one particular reason I stated previously. Take for example, today I haven&amp;#8217;t used it at all, and it&amp;#8217;s a good thing I haven&amp;#8217;t missed everything going on there. Even better, if tomorrow and the days after, I will no longer think about signing in. But I still think about friends who suddenly couldn&amp;#8217;t contact me. Still, I believe the majority will not notice or care much about it. These people already have about 500 to 2000 friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class='image_and_caption'&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img title='I just want to be happy' src='/images/happy.jpg' alt='happiness' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;b&gt;Image credit © &lt;a href='http://ray.9gag.com/' target='_blank'&gt;9GAG&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class='section'&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Let us be grateful to people who make us happy; they are the charming gardeners who make our souls blossom.&lt;/code&gt; &amp;#8211; MARCEL PROUST&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class='section'&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;The truth is that our finest moments are most likely to occur when we are feeling deeply uncomfortable, unhappy, or unfulfilled. For it is only in such moments, propelled by our discomfort, that we are likely to step out of our ruts and start searching for different ways or truer answers.&lt;/code&gt; &amp;#8211; M. SCOTT PECK&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>First Post</title>
   <link href="http://www.rue-tuscany.com/website/first-post.html"/>
   <updated>2010-03-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>id:/website/first-post</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It was nice learning about &lt;a href='http://github.com/blog/272-github-pages'&gt;github pages&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href='http://wiki.github.com/mojombo/jekyll'&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;#8217;m still not quite done, but at least we have the basics for now. I have in mind several features to implement, and I hope to tweak the borrowed design further in order to reflect myself better as soon as I get time. The &lt;a href='http://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/'&gt;Markdown&lt;/a&gt; language seems to be a very logical way for writing posts. It is wonderful in a way that it allows us to focus better on the content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the process, I tested out this blog with a few different browsers: Firefox, Internet Explorer (IE) 8, Chrome, and Opera. Getting it to work with Firefox was not so straightforward. For example, how could a Firefox browser possibly give us an IE 6 warning about missing plugin while the browser is obviously not IE. It was only later that I figured out that it had something to do with the default layout. Including the Google Analytic codes eliminated the warning. I still don&amp;#8217;t understand because the error message was kind of misleading. I was relieved that it did not take me too long to narrow down to this. It usually takes me more time on similar issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This command: jekyll &amp;#8211;server &amp;#8211;auto &amp;#8211;pygments, is really handy to compile everything locally from the terminal, and we get an updated site (posts, layouts). The last step will be to upload all the files that have been turned into HTML to the web server. This can be done with Github or rsync.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the limited time to really understand and take away lessons from Jekyll and Github, I was very excited spending time with them. It is like a small project that I can keep working on even though I encountered some difficulty at first. I wish I had the same enthusiasm for things that I&amp;#8217;m supposed to put my energy into. More to come soon :-).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;February 28, 2011: &lt;a href='/website/starting-over.html'&gt;Site updated&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src='/images/cup.png' alt='alt hope' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 
</feed>
