<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>Train of Thoughts to Tuscany</title>
 <link href="http://www.rue-tuscany.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://www.rue-tuscany.com"/>
 <updated>2011-03-09T23:36:10-05:00</updated>
 <id>http://www.rue-tuscany.com/</id>
 <author>
   <name>Jennifer Lee</name>
   <email>leecarrot@gmail.com</email>
 </author>
 
 
 <entry>
   <title>Starting Over</title>
   <link href="http://www.rue-tuscany.com/website/starting-over.html"/>
   <updated>2011-02-28T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>id:/website/starting-over</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This site used to be hosted on &lt;a href='http://hostingrails.com/'&gt;HostingRails&lt;/a&gt;, and have since used two different domain names: rosebery.ca, miffytrail.com. The main reason for recent domain name switches was simply because I did not find the name truly resonated with me. I wish I could have used my full name, but that will be utterly impossible, given how many Jennifer Lee(s) are out there&amp;#8230; Hence, a blog redesign, and the name &amp;#8216;rue-tuscany&amp;#8217; a.k.a &amp;#8216;Train of Thoughts to Tuscany&amp;#8217;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have experienced difficulty in keeping up a regular blog, so my apology to those who stopped by this site last year. Blogging at least once per week would be the most to expect for now. But again, don&amp;#8217;t take my words for it. My cognitive ability has somewhat decreased since my graduate courses were completed over a year ago. Thinking that I could focus solely on my master thesis, and therefore postponed looking for jobs does not really work out for me. Perhaps it&amp;#8217;s time to admit I no longer have the capacity to engage in research intensive types of project, or that I failed to be passionate enough in what I&amp;#8217;m doing. Taking that into account, it will be reasonable to save money for the hosting. &lt;a href='http://heroku.com/'&gt;Heroku&lt;/a&gt; came in just at the right time to host this site for free. A very good explanation on how to set it up to work with Jekyll can be found at this &lt;a href='http://datamangling.com/2010/07/Jekyll-on-Heroku'&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Love and Hate Relationship with Facebook</title>
   <link href="http://www.rue-tuscany.com/privacy/facebook-privacy.html"/>
   <updated>2010-05-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>id:/privacy/facebook-privacy</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I did not persist until the end. Instead of deleting my Facebook account, I deactivated it after further consideration. Many people have come to rely on Facebook&amp;#8217;s messaging system as a practical way for easy and fast communications. However, it is not without any downside with regards to the emotional effect it brought along. There is something really wrong with excessive use that has fundamentally twisted our hopes and reality. There are many more important things awaiting us to do in the real world. I didn&amp;#8217;t regret I gave myself a break from Facebook, and I remind myself that I need not spend too much time on it if I ever reactivate it again, which I just did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After this experience, and by following closely privacy news surrounding Facebook, we ought to understand the many different viewpoints people have towards Facebook. Unfortunately, the company&amp;#8217;s stance has not changed very much despite all the complaints and pressures from privacy advocates and regulators. While the founder of Facebook thinks &lt;a href='http://www.zephoria.org/thoughts/archives/2010/05/14/facebook-and-radical-transparency-a-rant.html'&gt;radical transparency&lt;/a&gt; is good for everyone, the company does not seem to exhibit the same kind of transparency in return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, &lt;a href='http://joindiaspora.com/'&gt;Diaspora&lt;/a&gt; is a social network planned to be built as a better alternative to Facebook. It will be interesting to see how this open and decentralized network can change the game. If there is one thing that has been quite successful to keep me as a user, it will be that we don&amp;#8217;t know those people in our contact list as much as we thought we did. Once in a while, there will be random nice surprises from people who suddenly decide to get in touch, or those who express their common interest in the stuff we share. It can be felt as a kind of emotional support and warmthness.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Happy Mother's Day!</title>
   <link href="http://www.rue-tuscany.com/random/mothers-day.html"/>
   <updated>2010-05-09T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>id:/random/mothers-day</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It is now 2.57 am, and I am still figuring out some stuff for Monday. I came across this beautiful doodle from Google. I just realized it was already Mother&amp;#8217;s Day. It had been cloudy and rainy yesterday. I hope the day will soon brighthen up a bit for this occasion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I heard about Mother&amp;#8217;s Day from my little cousin just a few days ago, but I forgot when the day actually came. How sweet she was when she said my little teddy bear would have loved to prepare a gift for me, but it was unable to (as I have been like the teddy&amp;#8217;s mum). So on behalf of the teddy, she made a drawing for me. Thank you to both ^_^.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would also like to wish all the mothers in this world, a Happy Mother&amp;#8217;s Day. Thank you for all the love you have given to us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src='/images/mothers-day.png' alt='alt google' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>In Pursuit of Happiness</title>
   <link href="http://www.rue-tuscany.com/well-being/happiness.html"/>
   <updated>2010-05-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>id:/well-being/happiness</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have been thinking of what it means to be really happy. Feeling as if I have been pursuing the so-called happiness relentlessly. My plans are not always carried out with full consideration beforehand, which often makes me feel guilty for failing to adhere to certain norms I set for myself. Just to be happy, I&amp;#8217;m always willing to invest in anything within my capabilities whenever deemed appropriate. This includes the monetary route as well, such as buying things and services to meet my curiosity and experimental nature. The later is more for having someone to talk to, or simply for developing a friendship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The kind of happiness obtained in such manners will not last forever. Buying physical things often falls short of our expectation, and we wake up feeling more disappointed than before. The road to happiness always foresees several wrong choices, which unfortunately are needed in order to make better-informed decision in the future. This article from &lt;a href='http://www.spring.org.uk/2010/04/six-psychological-reasons-consumer-culture-is-unsatisfying.php'&gt;Psyblog, Six Psychological Reasons Consumer Culture is Unsatisfying&lt;/a&gt; gives a nice insight to the overall implications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src='/images/rainybear.jpg' alt='alt rainybear' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image credit: &lt;a href='http://www.flickr.com/photos/jopscat/'&gt;jopscat&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am still going to get things I need. Only that there is this growing tendency to think twice before purchasing things that look only attractive, but do not contain any significant values or long term benefits. I appreciate beautiful clothes. However, past lessons have taught me that I only need to replace clothes that have almost worn out. These are my favorite T-shirts, pants, or jeans, which I am happy enough to wear in different colors daily, or in slightly different styles interchangably. I used to be an avid snacker, but my health has gotten more sensitive to these food recently. I am cutting back of the amount. It will be too bad if my time is spent falling sick again from cough, throat infection, or stomach flu. These food already contain little or no nutrients. In some cases, they lead to obesity too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever I shop now, I know exactly what I need. It helps to get myself out of the stores as soon as my chores are done. All of these are simply life changes evident on the material level. On a higher level, things have never been the same since the post break-up from a four years relationship, which also happened to be my first. It has been a year and a half today without any news whatsoever. It was hard at first, but time has been my best friend. Holding no grudges, no bitterness. Does every break-up always have to lead to awkwardness, hiding, always thinking the other person is never going to be forgiving? If that is really the case, it is such a pity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I&amp;#8217;m progressing in some aspects, I have to admit my life is not as productive as what I want it to be at this moment. It feels rather empty or blend. Last year, I started to experience a symptom of withdrawal. I guess there are some side effects from always trying to find ways to heal ourselves. That&amp;#8217;s why psychologists are there for us. Nevertheless, I still believe &lt;a href='http://fengshuiforward.com/330/the-most-powerful-cure-ourselves/'&gt;the best cure is ourselves&lt;/a&gt;. The side effects I meant are the inferiority complex, analysis-paralysis, and &lt;a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Impostor_syndrome'&gt;impostor syndrome&lt;/a&gt; that I recently find myself struggling with. I think I am going to have a big trouble awaiting if I let this procrastination habit continues. I am so close to finishing my master degree, and it is just happening at this time of the year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the positive note, I have this new appreciation of being related to others. I learned the hard way the need to cherish love and true friendships, for we never know what we have until it is taken away from us. It will take some time to rebuild my connections again. And I realise it is not going to be easy, as I still find myself thinking twice as much before I act or speak. First, I need to let go of the fear or paranoia of not being liked by others at the very beginning of a friendship. I feel I have been very unfair to those whom I met briefly at graduate school. They are nice people too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src='/images/contentment.png' alt='alt contentment' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before deleting my Facebook account, I spent a lot of time liking other people&amp;#8217;s posts, looking through their pictures and comments. I did that because I really found their stuff nice and interesting. At the same time, I also realise it is very important for everyone of us to receive any kind of appreciation or praises once in a while. There is nothing wrong if we can make someone&amp;#8217;s day better. I really do not mind doing that even though my own stuff on FB do not usually receive similar kind of interests. However, the more I do that, I will then ask myself why I have nothing better to do, or why there is such a serious lack of love and passion in my life. This has been unexpected. How easy this is turning against myself soon, and I did that a lot everyday. I think I can be very unreasonable and lacking of self control sometimes. As my number of friends are growing to more than 250, I also find the news streams are getting way too much noise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have 13 more days to go before my account is completely deleted by Facebook. It was not an easy decision even though I had spent considerable amount of time weighing the pros and cons. I have very few good friends on Facebook who uses the messaging system to keep in touch with me. There are also friends I made through Fluff Friends who can be very supportive at times. The biggest cons is clearly the fact that &lt;a href='http://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2010/04/facebook-timeline'&gt;Facebook is eroding our privacy as time goes&lt;/a&gt;. The way they do it is getting more tricky, and we as users do not have as much authority anymore. We are viewed only as their product that has a lot of valuable data to contribute in their effort to dominate the web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many who are not concerned about their privacy. But there are also those who care, and decide to just share information that is not private. They have thoroughly gone through their privacy settings. I was doing the same just before this. But I dislike Facebook&amp;#8217;s latest policy after constantly finding myself readjust the privacy settings. I also need to get away for one particular reason I stated previously. Take for example, today I haven&amp;#8217;t used it at all, and it&amp;#8217;s a good thing I haven&amp;#8217;t missed everything going on there. Even better, if tomorrow and the days after, I will no longer think about signing in. But I still think about friends who suddenly couldn&amp;#8217;t contact me. Still, I believe the majority will not notice or care much about it. These people already have about 500 to 2000 friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src='/images/happy.jpg' alt='alt happiness' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image credit: &lt;a href='http://ray.9gag.com/'&gt;9GAG&lt;/a&gt;. The following quotes are my favorites from &lt;a href='http://destinyxplorer.blogspot.com/'&gt;Master Goh&amp;#8217;s blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class='section'&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us be grateful to people who make us happy; they are the charming gardeners who make our souls blossom. ~ MARCEL PROUST ~&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class='section'&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The truth is that our finest moments are most likely to occur when we are feeling deeply uncomfortable, unhappy, or unfulfilled. For it is only in such moments, propelled by our discomfort, that we are likely to step out of our ruts and start searching for different ways or truer answers. ~ M. SCOTT PECK ~&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>First Post</title>
   <link href="http://www.rue-tuscany.com/website/first-post.html"/>
   <updated>2010-03-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>id:/website/first-post</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It was nice learning about &lt;a href='http://github.com/blog/272-github-pages'&gt;github pages&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href='http://wiki.github.com/mojombo/jekyll'&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;#8217;m still not quite done, but at least we have the basics for now. I have in mind several features to implement, and I hope to tweak the borrowed design further in order to reflect myself better as soon as I get time. The &lt;a href='http://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/'&gt;Markdown&lt;/a&gt; language seems to be a very logical way for writing posts. It is wonderful in a way that it allows us to focus better on the content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the process, I tested out this blog with a few different browsers: Firefox, Internet Explorer (IE) 8, Chrome, and Opera. Getting it to work with Firefox was not so straightforward. For example, how could a Firefox browser possibly give us an IE 6 warning about missing plugin while the browser is obviously not IE. It was only later that I figured out that it had something to do with the default layout. Including the Google Analytic codes eliminated the warning. I still don&amp;#8217;t understand because the error message was kind of misleading. I was relieved that it did not take me too long to narrow down to this. It usually takes me more time on similar issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This command: jekyll &amp;#8211;server &amp;#8211;auto &amp;#8211;pygments, is really handy to compile everything locally from the terminal, and we get an updated site (posts, layouts). The last step will be to upload all the files that have been turned into HTML to the web server. This can be done with Github or rsync.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the limited time to really understand and take away lessons from Jekyll and Github, I was very excited spending time with them. It is like a small project that I can keep working on even though I encountered some difficulty at first. I wish I had the same enthusiasm for things that I&amp;#8217;m supposed to put my energy into. More to come soon :-).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;February 28, 2011: &lt;a href='/website/starting-over.html'&gt;Site updated&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src='/images/cup.png' alt='alt hope' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 
</feed>
